I'm finally here.
The Ōoku.
I'll take your offerings
for the Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
Form a line.
The Ōoku is off-limits to men.
Only women with a pass may enter.
Is this the Ōoku?
Oh my! This is so exciting!
Thank you!
Thank goodness! They've kept their shape.
Know what they are?
I don't, but I'm sure they're delicious.
Rice balls with magnolia leaf miso.
They smell good.
- Would you like one?
- What?
My grandmother gave me
plenty for everyone in the Ōoku.
I'm here to work in the Ōoku.
My name is Kame.
I also begin work in the Ōoku today.
My name is Asa.
Simply irresistible...
The charred smell
of miso and magnolia leaves.
Um, you can try one too if you'd like.
I would appreciate that.
Hey!
You two over there.
Lady Asa and Lady Kame, right?
Wow, you're both
as beautiful as I've heard.
Much obliged.
Nice to meet you!
The long journey must have been tough.
I'm Sakashita, a palace guard.
As a doorman of the Ōoku,
I watch over the Nanatsu Gate here.
Now, let me take your luggage.
Thank you.
However, this is all I have.
I can carry it myself.
I see.
But Lady Kame,
you have a lot of luggage.
Master Sakashita, please try
one of my grandmother's rice balls.
Oh, they smell so nice!
Shall I prepare
a special love potion for you?
Whoa! Who the heck are you?
Just a humble medicine seller.
I sell such things as British love potions
that can effortlessly enchant any woman--
I'm not interested!
You're a fishy fellow, huh?
What's with your outfit, anyway?
Lady Asa, Lady Kame.
You should stay away from guys like him.
Nothing good will come of it.
Well, let's continue
this conversation later.
You're quite a character!
See you!
Hiramoto, we're in the Ōoku now.
Behave yourself.
Hold on, Saburomaru.
I sense beautiful women approaching.
Aren't those two gorgeous?
Get a hold of yourself!
Keep messing around,
and I'll throw out your pass!
Don't be so uptight.
Let's enjoy ourselves.
Just for confirmation,
show me your passes.
What? Where is it?
Senior maids Madam Awashima
and Madam Mugitani are waiting for you.
First impressions are everything.
Good luck.
I will introduce myself right away.
Don't forget to eat your rice ball!
Thanks!
Hey, you!
Do you require that love potion?
The Ōoku is not
a place for people like you.
It is reserved for the women
gathered to serve His Majesty.
The Nanatsu Gate is as far as you can go.
Should you enter without permission,
you'll be beheaded on sight.
See you later, Medicine Seller!
And I don't need any love potions!
Huh?
One, two...
Greetings.
This is Madam Awashima,
who deals with visitors.
I'm Mugitani.
I manage daily tasks and events.
My name is Asa.
My name is Kame.
We look forward to working with you.
Please, drink.
This is the water of
the Water Goddess, who watches over us.
All women who live in the Ōoku
drink this water every morning.
Under the protection of the Water Goddess,
we are always prepared
to produce a successor.
Next, take the most cherished
belongings you've brought from home
and offer them to this well.
Throw away the person you were until now.
The person I was until now...
Throw away?
We all become property of His Majesty.
- We must offer our hearts and bodies.
- They're only objects.
That... That's right!
Here we go...
My grandmother gave me these rice balls.
I thought we could all...
enjoy them together... but, um...
- Wha--
- Oh!
Now, I'm sure
this has helped strengthen your resolve.
Greetings, Madam Utayama.
If you cling onto
all your cherished items,
you will be unable to perform your duties.
With all due respect,
do our duties require
throwing away our cherished belongings?
My, you certainly speak your mind,don't you?
I've practiced writing since an early age.
Due to my accomplishments,
I was given the opportunity to come here.
Therefore, my father has instructed
me to continue my studies.
However, I have nothing
too important to throw away.
You have nothing that precious?
- This comb is from my grandmother.
- Kame!
She told me to keep it for good luck.
Stop! There's no need to do this.
Yes, there is.
I have to do well here in the Ōoku.
Something... has taken form.
You'll get wet.
M-Madam Utayama!
I'm sorry you had to witness this!
You two! What are you doing?
Show some respect.
This is Madam Utayama,
manager of the Ōoku,
and this is the concubine Lady Botan!
Madam Awashima, I see
this newcomer has perfect manners.
I apologize! It seems she lacks
the proper mindset to perform her duties.
I am ready to dedicate
my life to my duties.
The Ōoku is not a place
for you to find fulfillment.
What do you mean?
How dare you talk back to Madam Utayama!
Rather than forging your own path,
you must contribute to the Ōoku.
Both you and I are here for that purpose.
As you fulfill your role,
you will gain a higher perspective.
A higher perspective...
In time, you will realize that
the doubt in your heart was insignificant.
I shall also bear this in mind!
Madam Utayama, let's go.
We mustn't keep the gentlemen waiting.
Madam Mugitani,
you try not to go overboard either.
Yes, Lady Botan!
Master Sakashita?
What?
What is all this commotion about?
You didn't know about the ceremony?
I smelled an opportunity to make a profit.
Unbelievable.
Lady Yukiko, the consort,
has given birth to His Majesty's child.
This great festival is
to celebrate the occasion.
Isn't a ceremony like this
normally held before the birth?
Hey! That's because...
It's complicated.
Madam Utayama will be arriving shortly!
Excuse me! Please stop!
That's Madam Utayama's...
It's fine.
I apologize for keeping you waiting.
My name is Saburomaru Tokita.
This is Hiramoto Saga.
We only just arrived too.
Why was the Birth Celebratory Ceremony
postponed two months ago--
Please, leave everything to me.
We were called here
because we cannot leave everything to you.
It is as the report states.
Simple lack of preparation doesn't explain this.
I already reported
this matter to Councilor Otomo.
I was instructed to
deal with this internally.
Councilor Otomo?
I am of the Otomo family,
and I serve in the Ōoku.
My name is Botan.
It is said that Lady Yukiko
had a very difficult childbirth
and is completely exhausted.
Some suggest that this is because
the ceremony was not held two months ago.
In other words, Madam Utayama,
you are the one responsible.
I understand that.
That is why we made
the rare decision to hold the ceremony
after the childbirth.
Our duty is to oversee the Ōoku--
The Ōoku belongs to His Majesty.
Know your place.
I apologize.
But the government
sent us here to supervise and ensure
that the ceremony proceeds smoothly.
You must have heard this
from Councilor Otomo.
Of course.
However, I ask that
you refrain from your vulgar prying
and your excessive interactions
with the maids of the Ōoku.
This is the Ōoku,
where men are usually forbidden to enter.
You may be doing your duty,
but rule breakers shall be punished,
no matter who they are.
Very well.
Please make arrangements
so that we can begin our work tomorrow.
Understood.
Suma is dry.
No.
Kiyo is also dry.
Fuki is not dry.
- Matron.
- Your Majesty!
I am dry.
Lady Fuki again?
His Majesty is rather fervent, isn't he?
The Ōoku employs roughly 2,000 maids.
You are to prepare breakfast
for everyone before sunrise.
What?!
Sorry!
First, you'll prepare meals
for 50 people in the fourth building.
When you're ready,
it will go up to 100 people.
A hundred?
Be sure to finish
your own breakfast before you begin.
Understood.
Your writing is so neat, Asa!
How early do we need to
wake up in time for "before sunrise"?
I used to make breakfast
for my neighbors every day.
I'm sure it'll be fine.
I've never even made breakfast before.
I hear Lord Saburomaru is
the concubine Lady Fuki's younger brother.
He is the third son of the Tokita family.
That doesn't change anything.
We shall proceed in earnest
for the Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
The Tokita family
has been gaining momentum lately.
I'd like to avoid fighting them
and giving them additional leverage.
I say this
as a member of the Otomo family.
Madam Utayama, you too are
under the Otomo family's protection.
Perhaps we should let them feel
as though they've done some work.
The two of you will have
the rank of maidservant.
You will sleep
in a room on the second floor.
You will serve Madam Awashima...
Two thousand maids?
And only eight of them
get to serve His Majesty as a concubine.
- For cleaning...
- The longest journey begins with one step.
...take the initiative.
Yes, ma'am!
Right...
They are the concubines.
Be sure to make way for them.
We are like decorative flowers
used to enhance Lady Fuki...
The concubines are here!
It appears His Majesty
only has eyes for Lady Fuki now.
Didn't you hear me?!
Sorry!
I hope His Majesty would pick
the flowers too once in a while.
His Majesty first spoke to me
when I was still a mere bud.
I'm sure the time will come
for all of you too.
L-Lady Fuki!
Greetings...
My, how... beautiful you are.
You must be new.
Yes, ma'am! My name is Kame.
Greetings.
How long are you going
to waste time selling medicine?
Come on, we're closing!
I have more to offer than medicine.
And I'm not wasting any time.
Aren't you drinking?
No, I've decided not to drink
until our work here is done.
You're a dull man, you know?
This task may be
more difficult than I thought.
All we have to do is look at pretty girls.
Quite the perk.
The Ōoku does more than
just produce His Majesty's successor.
I get that.
The shogunate and the Ōoku
are two sides of the same coin.
Power relations on the outside
are maintained by the work done here.
Never mind politics.
If no successor is produced,
what's the point of the Ōoku,
I wonder?
Oh, I don't mean to
speak ill of your elder sister.
Our duty is to oversee
the Birth Celebratory Ceremony,
but people outside the Ōoku
are targeting Madam Utayama.
That old woman...
I don't like her.
I see why it's hard for those outside
to carry out their plans in the Ōoku.
I suppose that's why they wish
to reduce Madam Utayama's influence.
I can't stand that look on her face,
as if she rules the world.
It must be hard to be
the third son of the Tokita family.
You got this job thanks to Lady Fuki,
so you'll need to produce good results.
Why was the Birth Celebratory Ceremony
postponed two months ago?
There must be a reason.
Perhaps Madam Utayama
has held power in the Ōoku for too long.
Hey, that water smelled really bad, right?
Yeah... It smelled rancid.
How do Madam Awashima
and the others drink it so easily?
- Look out for fire!
Is it because
they're doing it for His Majesty?
Oh, I wish I could become
a concubine like Lady Fuki already.
She was very pretty.
When we passed by Lady Fuki today,
Madam Mugitani's eyes lit up too.
It's Lady Fuki!
How pretty...
All of the concubines are pretty.
Even yours did, right, Asa?
Personally,
rather than become a glamorous concubine,
I'd prefer to learn a skill.
Right now, my goal is
to take on the role of official scribe.
The intensity of His Majesty's affection
towards Lady Fuki as of late...
Lady Yukiko's child
was another girl, you see.
Lady Fuki must be very skilled.
At this rate,
His Majesty's successor will be...
Asa, you seem like
you could do anything well.
I don't know if I can
make it here in the Ōoku.
You'll be fine.
Let's do our best together.
Lady Yukiko hasn't been picked for some time.
Lady Fuki's influence continues to grow.
As for Lady Botan of the Otomo family...
She doesn't seem interested in night work.
Asa!
I'm really glad I met you, Asa.
Me too.
We start early tomorrow.
Let's get some sleep.
Okay. Good night.
Good night.
All manner of misfortune
Sin and defilement
Purify
Cleanse
By the will of heaven
- The Water Goddess is not fond of fire.
- Protect us
Grant us good fortune
Madam Utayama.
Greetings.
The recently postponed
Birth Celebratory Ceremony
is now three days away.
Many guests will arrive on that day.
In the few days we have left,
I want everyone to remain focused
as we make preparations.
Only women with a pass may enter!
I'll take your offerings for the ceremony!
No men are to enter the Ōoku!
Form a line!
Is it still... far away?
I shall now announce personnel
for the Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
Awashima will coordinate
this Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
Her role will change
from head housemaid to greeter of dignitaries.
From decorations to food and drink,
everything must be handled efficiently.
Everyone is to follow
Awashima's instructions.
There may be over 100 participants
at this Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
From seating arrangements
to guidance upon leaving,
there is no room for error.
Mugitani's role will change from housemaid
to head housemaid to take on this duty.
Mugitani will receive support
from somebody with knowledge of relations
between the shogunate and powerful lords.
Concubine Otomo.
Mugitani, be sure
to seek guidance from Otomo.
Yes, ma'am!
And although she just arrived yesterday,
I have something to ask of Asa too.
She will act as a guide
for Saburomaru Tokita and Hiramoto Saga,
inspectors from the shogunate.
This may be unusual,
but I will assign Asa
the rank of housemaid.
May I ask you two to say a few words?
Well done, Asa!
My name is Saburomaru Tokita.
Lady Asa, I appreciate your assistance.
- Tokita? Is he related to Lady Fuki?
- He's so flippant.
...Madam Mugitani,
I'll be counting on your help!
To ensure that nothing is wrong
with our preparations,
they have come all this way,
though men are normally forbidden here.
Asa, make sure they understand
we do not need anyone overseeing us
by attending to them properly.
This is the Ōoku!
Everyone, devote yourselves to the Ōoku!
Go to your positions immediately.
Yes, ma'am.
I wonder if Lady Asa
and Lady Kame are doing well.
Master Sakashita, what are
your expectations for those two?
Lady Asa should be fine,
but I'm worried about Lady Kame.
Girls who are too nice often struggle.
But with the successful girls,
they often change so much
that they're like different people
when you next see them.
Asa!
- I've been studying the ways of the Ōoku.
- Kame...
I'll help you guide the gentlemen.
I'll make sure to finish
my own duties afterward.
- Um...
- Okay?
I'll hold you to it.
Recently, there was another girl
who completely changed.
Where is she now?
I heard she left the Ōoku
and returned to the countryside.
You heard?
What was the name of this maid?
Why must I tell someone like you?!
The bedchamber lies up ahead.
To think that Lady Fuki
walked these halls yesterday
to go and perform her night work...
Oh my. How exciting!
I have learned a lot.
You have my gratitude.
Everything here is so fascinating.
Lady Asa, how long has it been
since you joined the Ōoku?
I'm impressed, Kame.
You're so knowledgeable.
The rice cake for the Birth Celebratory
Ceremony will go around the Ōoku.
Finally, it will be brought here,
where the official scribe will...
Saburomaru, which one do you prefer?
We're on the job. Cut it out!
No need to be shy.
Shh!
The purification salt
should have arrived by now.
It has been delayed due to bad weather.
I thought I might acquire some
from a local wholesaler, just in case.
Have Asa do it.
Lady Asa?
Kame!
Awashima, how many years
have you been in the Ōoku?
- I worked up an appetite!
- It has been six years.
I have made a point
of giving slightly more work
to those with talent and motivation.
That includes you too.
But to take on the role
of housemaid on one's first day...
Not even Kitagawa--
Madam Awashima, take a look.
Does this look like
the work of a newcomer?
Lady Asa wrote this.
Everyone loves themselves.
We all want to be recognized, loved, and valued.
We cannot satisfy these wishes alone.
We expect our neighbors to satisfy us,
but we are also compared to them.
Those same people
compete with us for limited positions.
I will strive to improve.
I just want to talk with you.
I feel like this has been
the longest day of my life...
So this is what
the private rooms look like!
I hope I get one of my own soon!
You're amazing, Asa.
I doubt anyone has ever been appointed
to an official position within one day.
Madam Utayama chose me
for this role. I have to work hard.
Okay, I'll leave you to it.
What? You're leaving already?
I just wanted to see the private rooms.
I'm a lowly maid. I need to
prepare bedding and stuff.
I see.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah! See you tomorrow.
The umbrella...?
My apologies.
I left that here.
When I changed rooms,
I left it behind.
Did you previously use this room?
That's right.
My name is Kitagawa.
Lady Kitagawa, my name is Asa.
Come now. You needn't be so formal.
Judging from your kimono,
you must be the official scribe.
Such titles are
only meaningful within the Ōoku.
I visited the Ōoku
with my father as a child.
The Birth Celebratory Ceremony
inspired me back then,
and I've dreamed of
working in the Ōoku ever since.
Behind the beautiful dancers,
the scribe wielded
her brush with such strength.
I remember how that sight captivated me.
That was supposed to be my role
in the recent Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
I heard it was canceled due to some issue.
That's right.
This is a wonderful brush.
Why don't you apply
for the role of official scribe?
I couldn't possibly.
I'm still far from that.
I'd like to talk with you again.
When it's just us two, never mind ranks.
Thank you very much.
Can you look after that doll for me?
Huh?
I'll come to see her again too.
Take care. Rest well.
I will.
Good night!
Lady... Kitagawa...
All manner of misfortune...
Come on, stay awake.
Sorry...
I'm always relying on you.
It's all right.
Cleanse
By the will of heaven
- Let's go!
- Yeah!
- Father!
Good girls.
What is this mess?!
Didn't I tell you
to finish this yesterday?
Did you forget?
No, it's not that...
I'm sorry! I'll hurry up and do it now!
Starting now? They'll never dry!
That's why it needed to be done yesterday!
This isn't something
you could just put off 'til today.
Besides, you have
other work for today, don't you?
Good grief.
Aren't you ashamed
of such half-baked work?
Is something the matter?
L-Lady Asa! Her duties!
She didn't finish her work!
My deepest apologies.
I failed to check.
Unacceptable.
What about the purification salt
I asked for yesterday?
I wonder how that worked out.
Yes, ma'am.
I sent someone right after
receiving your instructions.
It arrived first thing this morning.
- Oh...
- Impressive work!
From Lady Asa, at least.
But then there's you.
Madam Awashima!
Kame didn't wake up
to prepare breakfast this morning either.
What do you make of that?
It wasn't like that.
It's my fault for not asking Lady Kame to help.
Though it was a task meant for two people,
I thought I could handle it alone.
I was misguided.
So in other words,
the only thing
you can do is flirt with men!
- Don't say--
- Madam Mugitani!
Men distracted you from
yesterday's work, and today you overslept!
I don't know whether you're lazy or easy!
- But if you saw--
- Well, well!
Was I not thoughtful enough?
- I didn't mean--
- What did you mean?
That's enough!
Lady Kame, collect your things
and move to Madam Mugitani's room.
You are to learn from scratch
exactly what your duties entail.
And Madam Mugitani.
Please behave as an Ōoku maid should.
- Yes, ma'am.
- I was the one at fault, so...
My, my.
You were just promoted.
Will you take on the task
of instructing Lady Kame too?
Yes, ma'am. If that is my duty.
- I humbly accept it.
- What...?
I will...
I will be careful
from now on! I'll work hard!
- No!
- I'm sorry!
I'll take responsibility
for dealing with this girl!
- I'm sorry!
- Kame--
Such beautiful hands...
It seems that one of the maids
fell ill two months ago,
and then left the Ōoku.
And nobody has been told clearly
why the Birth Celebratory
Ceremony was postponed.
Should we get
the shogunate to look into this?
What a splendid device.
This is a pair of scales.
Scales?
So how does it work?
And what does it measure?
What people...
What people...?
...cannot see, and how far away that is.
You...
You're not really serious
about your duties, are you?
It's obvious.
I'm trying... my best.
But I can't wake up early.
I try to remember what I'm told,
but I always end up forgetting.
I can't do a good job like other people,
and I constantly get left behind.
What did you even come to the Ōoku for?
Why are you here?!
I've seen your type before.
Just because you're easy on the eye
you think you can slack off!
All you care about is
getting into His Majesty's bed!
That's not true...
It's here!
No! Stop! Let go!
If you plan to take this job seriously,
you won't need all this!
No!
Didn't I tell you?
Cross this line and you'll lose your head!
A mononoke
has appeared.
Stop!
What?
This is an emergency!
In the back?
Hey! You can't come in--
What are these?
What happened?
The kaleidoscope...
Master Sakashita!
Where's the intruder...?
Madam Awashima!
Above?
- Don't go!
- Wait--
Madam Awashima?
Yes. It seems she heard a terrible scream
that sounded like Madam Mugitani.
Has it gone?
Wait--
What's all the commotion?
Kame!
She's alive.
Was Lady Kame the only one here?
I heard Madam Mugitani was also here.
It helps that you're so calm.
Is Kame...?
She'll wake up...
- Looks like...
- Huh?
I didn't make it on time.
- That rumbling sound...
- What is it?
Mugitani.
This is... not the work of any human.
- Who are you?!
- Not a human...?
I'm simply... a medicine seller.
You're guilty of intruding
into the Ōoku and causing disorder!
Right now, you're facing something
that cannot be slain by that sword.
This is the work of a mononoke.
- Mono...
- ...noke?
The cause of these apparitions...
- Apparitions?
- There is no such thing in the Ōoku!
Allow me
to slay this mononoke!
As the wet floor dries, a circle appears.
This mononoke...
Once an ayakashi, its name is Karakasa.
Madam Mugitani...
What is that noise?
I have identified... its Form.
Form?
The apparitions can only be quelled
if I slay the mononoke.
The kaleidoscope...
However, the power of a human
cannot slay a mononoke.
And so, I have this sword.
Kon is one of the
eight swords of Yin and Yang.
This great sword of the realm of Shuga
is entrusted to the 64 guardians.
It is also known as
the Sacred Sword!
Why didn't you slay it
with that sword immediately?
Drawing this sword
requires certain conditions.
Conditions?
Form.
Truth.
Reason.
Without these three elements,
I cannot draw the sword.
Truth is the way things appear.
Reason is the true nature of the passions
that smolder here in the Ōoku.
Do you mean that
if you show the sword these three elements,
you can slay this so-called mononoke?
Absolutely.
And in order to present
these three elements...
- Sakashita.
- Yes, ma'am!
- Provide this man with a pass.
- Madam Utayama?
I want you to destroy
this thing you call "Karakasa."
You are not to speak a word
of tonight's incident to anybody.
And until the end
of the Birth Celebratory Ceremony,
Mugitani is not dead.
What?
Do you understand, Awashima?
I... understand.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I would like to
ask you all to share with me...
your own Truths... and Reasons.
All manner of misfortune
Sin and defilement
Purify--
Is the water delicious? Heavenly...
Wait.
The Water Goddess, right?
Grant us good fortune
Could I ask you not to
dismiss Lady Kame yet?
We have no place
for those who are weak
or cannot contribute.
We can usually tell who they are
within the first three days.
I will leave you to deal with Kame.
Who's that guy?
A peddler from the Nanatsu Gate.
Everyone, please listen.
Mugitani had to return to
her family home, suddenly.
- What's going on?
- Come on now...
She left early this morning,
so she couldn't say goodbye.
Look.
She who carries a heavy burden
gains the strength to climb the next step.
I would like to
appoint Asa as head housemaid
and have her take over from Mugitani.
Head housemaid?
Has this ever happened before?
Lady Asa...
Can I entrust you with it?
Please, leave it to me.
It seems the maid we talked about
never actually made it home.
What?
That maid's name is...
Why is there a peddler in the Ōoku?
You ought to be beheaded!
Why don't you ask Madam Utayama?
Madam Utayama is
a powerful political figure.
I'd like to follow her example.
What? A sword?
There's a maid I'd like to ask you about.
Does the water taste good?
Lady Kitagawa...
Sometimes one must discard
something in order to move forward.
Lady Asa, I wonder what you will discard.
All I had were things I wished to discard.
But some things must not be discarded.
Not all of them...
...are tangible.
Discard those, and you will dry out.
I have something
I wish to keep from drying out.
That is why... I must throw it away.
Lady Asa.
I don't want to...
I don't want to see Madam Mugitani.
It's fine.
You can work with me today.
Really?
Yes.
Could you take on the task
of attending to visitors
at the ceremony?
Madam Utayama, I am not your subordinate.
As a member of the Otomo family,
I deal only with the dynamics
between the Ōoku and the outside world.
You don't mince words.
We maids must not approach the bedchamber.
That is the rule of the Ōoku.
Is he a magician?
What's happening?
Karakasa... is close.
Karakasa?
I've got you now.
Could it be that your goal
is to cause problems
and jeopardize
my position as your superior?
Such neat writing.
You've got it wrong!
After meeting Asa here
in the Ōoku, I knew I was in trouble.
I could never do things the way she does.
At this rate, I'll be sent away.
So I thought
if I could catch His Majesty's eye...
Are you plaguing us
because we made you throw away your comb?
What?
There is no mononoke, is there?
Mononoke?
You hid Mugitani, didn't you?
You and Asa!
I don't know what this is about...
Did Asa put you up to all of this?!
You just do whatever you want
and slack off on any job you don't like!
- There's nothing more cowardly!
- Stop!
Is this a dream?
Just follow him!
That sneaky look!
Nasty little girl!
Why?!
Madam Utayama!
I never wanted to throw it away!
Forgive me!
It won't open!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I'm sorr--
I'll take... responsibility
for dealing with this girl.
The Medicine Seller and
the two inspectors are causing a commotion.
What?
They say there's a mononoke!
- What's happening?
- Stay away!
Take her!
Wait--
This one... is beyond saving.
So it turns humans into rainwater?
You'll find Lady Kame
by the earthen floor.
Kame!
Two months ago,
a maid disappeared from the Ōoku.
Supposedly, she was going back
to her family home after being dismissed.
But she vanished like smoke,
and nobody knows where she is.
Did Madam Mugitani really
return home this morning?
And two months ago,
the Birth Celebratory
Ceremony was postponed.
Is this truly a coincidence?
No use, huh?
It's close.
What is that sound?
This matter is none of your business.
Didn't I tell you
that was reported to Councilor Otomo?
Tell me.
The missing maid. What is her name?
- Lady Kitagawa's...
- The former official scribe of the Ōoku...
Lady Kitagawa!
I have identified its Truth.
Lady Kitagawa is its Truth?
The mononoke...
is coming!
What is that?!
That right there is the mononoke,
Karakasa!
My apologies!
This is not yet Karakasa's final form.
Once it takes form in this world,
it will become unstoppable.
Awashima!
What is happening in the Ōoku?!
I intend to proceed as planned
with the Birth Celebratory Ceremony!
I'm too scared!
Asa, don't let go
of my hand until morning!
Okay.
Promise me! Let go,
and I'll never speak to you again.
I promise I won't let go.
No matter what, okay?
I met Lady Kitagawa.
You met her? But Lady Kitagawa is...
I mustn't dry out.
Huh?
I realized that.
Thanks to Lady Kitagawa,
I realized what was precious.
What I mustn't throw away.
That's good!
Yeah.
- So what was it?
- What?
Your precious thing.
I can't say.
What?! Tell me! Tell me!
I have something to tell you, Kame.
Hmm? What is it?
Something... important.
THE DAY OF THE BIRTH CELEBRATORY CEREMONY
Please don't get in our way.
What do you mean?
Madam Awashima passed away
after the Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
But why...
Performing the ceremony is merely a duty.
But many people have poured
their hearts and souls into this duty.
Can a job be that important?
Isn't it your job
to find fault with Madam Utayama
and bring about her downfall?
Lady Asa...
I'll send a messenger later.
Your work can wait until tomorrow.
Until the ceremony is over,
I will not allow
any disturbances in the Ōoku.
Grant us good fortune
So you spoke with Lady Kitagawa?
I thought the Medicine Seller
might be able to protect you, Asa.
Perhaps we can get closer
to the mononoke's Reason.
I do not know
what happened to Lady Kitagawa.
However...
However?
I now feel like I understand
Lady Kitagawa's feelings a little more.
Her feelings?
I'm sorry I couldn't be of more use.
No, it helps a little.
But the real mystery is Madam Utayama.
Why does she overlook these apparitions?
- Good point.
- Why go forward with the ceremony?
This is the Ōoku.
Sometimes, one must suppress
one's own feelings to do one's duty.
Based on whether one can do that,
I discern a person's suitability
for important roles.
- And Lady Kitagawa?
- I assessed her too.
That means
the mononoke's next target will be...
If you canceled the ceremony
like you did two months ago,
wouldn't that quell the apparitions?
Is that what you think?
Madam Utayama...
This is our duty.
You're right.
A mononoke? Spooky!
What about the ceremony?
People have died. It must be canceled--
The Birth Celebratory Ceremony
will be carried out as planned.
She looked like a mummified monk.
- Taking over from the late Madam Awashima...
- She was turned into a mummy.
Madam Awashima must have suffered greatly.
The day of
the Birth Celebratory Ceremony is upon us.
I would appreciate your full cooperation.
- His Majesty, his consort, and the baby.
- She isn't holding back.
- The event must proceed smoothly for them.
- Is this okay?
Now, let's begin
the Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
Everyone, please go to your positions.
Understood.
One, two...
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
Once the celebration starts,
the excitement is over all too soon.
Time waits for nobody.
I'm sorry you are unable to participate.
It's fine.
That's how it is behind the scenes.
At least if I'm here,
even when the mononoke--
I remember what you told me
when we first met.
That I would gain
a higher perspective as I progressed.
You were right, Madam Utayama.
I have now come to see
the insignificance of the pain
I'd experienced until that point.
When you stand above others,
you see things differently.
I saw a version of myself
that wasn't fazed by anything.
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
But at the same time,
something kept my emotions
from going astray.
That was...
Lady Kame.
Kame? Have you decided
how to deal with her?
- I have asked her to leave the Ōoku.
- I wanted to become a concubine.
I wanted to wear a beautiful kimono
for His Majesty...
You were decisive
and unswayed by emotion.
I also
wanted to eat together with Kame.
I wanted to spend more time
talking with her late into the night.
I have Lady Kitagawa to thank.
Kitagawa?
...against anybody!
Madam Utayama!
Is the mononoke here?
I threw it away...
Medicine Seller!
If we don't slay it soon,
we're in trouble!
I need the Reason.
If I don't draw my sword, we're done for!
Madam Utayama!
- What did you throw away?
- What?
It's trying to get through to this side!
Why is Karakasa after you?
I don't know!
The ceiling!
Here I go!
Saburomaru...?
All dried out...
Lady Kitagawa?
Lady Kitagawa!
Kitagawa...
I am...
all dried out.
So that's Lady Kitagawa?
Karakasa is...
manifesting in this world!
The first time I was urged
to throw away a cherished item,
I discarded it without hesitation.
By discarding it,
I resolved to become a different person.
Thanks to Madam Utayama's favor,
I steadily rose through the ranks.
There was another girl who entered
the Ōoku at the same time as me.
She struggled to fit in
and was so forgetful.
I became increasingly irritated with her.
I was given an important role
in the Birth Celebratory Ceremony.
On that day, I told her
to leave the Ōoku.
I thought I would worry less
and be able to focus on my duties.
That's what I thought...
But I was wrong.
I began wondering
what had changed within me.
I realized that I was all dried out.
Before I knew it,
I had lost the will to work.
I was stripped of my role.
I could no longer leave my room.
To become dried out,
I must have thrown something away.
Something important.
I'd thrown it away... down there.
No!
Kame--
Asa!
You'll be... okay!
Kitagawa?
Lady Kitagawa told me...
that I mustn't dry out.
Does she hold a grudge?
I don't believe
Lady Kitagawa holds a grudge
against anybody!
My duty...
This is...
my...
duty!
It stinks.
The Reason... has been revealed.
Form.
Truth.
Reason.
With these three elements in place,
I will release
my sword!
Release!
Karakasa.
Prepare to be cut down,
purified, and laid to rest.
Mononoke.
Go back!
Strike!
Forgive me.
And down!
- Is that the mononoke?
- Quiet!
Let's go together.
Your precious thing! Could it be...
I can't say!
Huh?
Dear me...
I shall fulfill my duty.
Ready!
I will now...
humbly take my leave.
Medicine Seller!
I still... cannot see
its Form.
She was smiling.
TO BE CONTINUED IN "THE ASHES OF RAGE"
Make me sick, I have a feeling I'm going to dry up
Wazurawasete kawaichau yokan ga suru wa
Love sick Love sick Love sick Love sick
Let me hear your voice, I'm gonna break down it's not AYAKASHI is it?
Koe wo kikasete kowarechau watashi masaka ayakashi?
Is it over already? Do you erase me? I become KATAMORI
Mou chiru? Kesu me? Katamari ni kasu mi
Is it over already? Do you erase me? I become AYAKASHI
Mou chiru? Kesu me? Ayakashi to kasu mi
Don't touch don't don't touch
Don't touch don't touch me
You stripped it from me, right?
Watashi wo hagashitan deshou
I touched you calling it "love"
Ai nante benri na namae wo tsukete furete
My heart is filled, yeah you are the only one
Kokoro ga mitasareta sou anata dake
Love sick, love sick, love sick Hey I'm chasing
Love sick, love sick, love sick nee oikakete
Love sick, love sick, love sick nee
Love sick, love sick, love sick Hey
What you sacrificed to get what you want
Hikari wo motomete suteta mono
Try measuring it on a scale
Hakari de hakatte mite goran
Were you able to change? Did you dry up?
Anata wa kawareta? Kawaita?
Naked disease that mourns in this fleeting world
Ukiyo ni nageku akarasama sick
No no no mononoke sweet sickness
No no no mononoke amai sick
No no no let it reach you
No no no otodoke
Is it over already? Do you erase me? I become KATAMORI
Mou chiru? Kesu me? Katamari ni kasu mi
Is it over already? Do you erase me?
Mou chiru? Kesu me?
I have a feeling I can't be myself
Watashi rashiku irarenai yokan ga suru wa
Love sick, love sick, love sick, love sick
I felt lonely and left behind by the world
Sekai ni sabishiku torinokosarete mieta
Love sick, love sick, love sick, love sick
I crave for love
Ai tarashi
Dumping the sickness that tortures me
Pokkari to aita nukarumi iro no ido ni
into the gaping hole of the muddy well
Watashi wo kurushimeru wazurai wo sutete
Let me embrace a new color
Atarashii atarashii atarashii iro dakasete
Love sick, love sick, love sick world
Everything that's been sacrificed is gasping for eternity
Hikari wo motomete suteta mono bakari ga towa wo aeideru
Watashi wa kawareta? kowareta?
Was I able to change? Did I break down?
Hitori ni shite the end of the end
Leave me alone at the end of the end
Kokoro no namida ga odoridashite
The tears inside me began to dance
And wet my pain blooming the flowers of sorrow
Kurushimi ga nurete ai ni hana ga saita
But do I suffer until I die?
Demo shinu made wazuracchau ka na
Will I be able to laugh someday?
Itsuka wa waraechau ka na
Will I be able to love?
Aiseru ka na
An obvious sickness
Akarasama sick
No no no mononoke
Am I sick?
No no no let it reach you
No no no otodoke
Embracing what can't be stripped away
Hagashite mo hagarenai mono wo dakishimete
Will I be able to see you again even if I break? Terribly sweet sickness
Kowaresou demo aesou? Hidoku amai yamai
THE PHANTOM IN THE RAIN
Subtitle translation by: Mari Koch